Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Howard Henderson Papers, 1867-1978 RL.00708
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Special Projects Series, 1914-1963 and undated (bulk 1957-1963)
  - International Offices and Special Assignments for Sam Meek Subseries, 1926-1961
    - Television Advertising, 1957-1959 (Box 9)
      (The Television Advertising folder includes a detailed memo on TV and movie theater commercials for overseas markets that discusses ways of keeping costs down and the division of responsibilities among representatives. There is also some material on the beginnings of TV advertising in Germany and a memo on services and clients of the Frankfurt office.)
    - U.S. Information Agency, 1956-1958 (Box 9)
      (The U.S. Information Agency material offers a glimpse of that agency's activities and its influence on overseas advertising business.)
  - New Business Presentation Subseries, 1956-1960
    Includes organizational charts of departments and offices throughout JWT, detailed information on competitors' services in relation to services rendered by J. Walter Thompson, and information on the Company's account team structure. It also includes a presentation prepared by Richard Brecker for Sunkist Growers.
    - 1956-1950 (Box 9)
    - Presentation to Sunkist Growers, 1960, 2 folders (Box 9)
- Cincinnati Office Series, 1918-1936
  Includes account figures of the Office from 1918 to 1935, a manual of policy letters and operating principles of the Office, sample letters of terms, correspondence on the Marietta Chair, Gruen Watch and Jergens accounts, notices of account termination, some advertising booklets, and correspondence relating to the 1935 closing of the Cincinnati Office. Much of the correspondence in this series is personal in nature and includes letters from James Webb Young, Stanley Resor, William Groom, Ruth Waldo, and H. T. Stanton.
  - Account figures, 1918-1932 (Box 9)
  - New Business Presentation, 1933[?] (Box 9)
  - Correspondence and other materials, 1923-1935, 2 folders (Box 9)
    (One folder contains notes by Henderson on a manuscript entitled World Peace Through Advertising (1924) and a summary of Henderson's 1928 speech Human Nature in Advertising.)
  - Advertisements booklets, 1925-1927 (Box 9)
    (The advertisement booklets are for Hooven and Allison (rope), Breneman (window shades), and Richardson and Company (roofs).)
  - Henderson's transfer to New York (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
- Personal Records and Information Series, 1925-1964
  Consists of biographical information on Howard Henderson, his personnel records from the 1950s, information on his investments, speeches that he gave, material concerning his search for an academic position in 1930, and correspondence and other information pertaining to three civic organizations of which he was a leading member: the Westchester County Civil Defense League, the Public Affairs Committee, and the International Recreation Association.
  Within sections materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Biographical records and speeches, 1925-1956 (Box 9)
  - Personnel matters, 1939-1961 (Box 9)
  - Financial records, 1930-1964 (Box 10)
  - Organizations:
    - International Recreation Association, 1956-1960 (Box 10)
    - Public Affairs Committee, 1954-1960 (Box 10)
    - Westchester County Civil Defense Council, 1941 (Box 10)
      (The file on the Civil Defense League includes correspondence with Helen Lansdowne Resor.) University teaching position, queries about, 1930)
- Clippings Series, 1944-1977
  Includes clippings from J.W.T. News, Advertising Age, The New York Times, and other publications.
  Articles on JWT are filed together at the beginning of the series. Arrangement thereafter is alphabetical by individual or company.
  - J. Walter Thompson Company and obituaries (Box 10)
  - A-C, 1945-1969 (Box 10)
  - D-G, 1944-1969 (Box 10)
  - H-L, 1946-1967 (Box 10)
  - M-O, 1946-1968 (Box 10)
  - P-R, 1947-1971 (Box 10)
  - S, 1946-1972 (Box 10)
  - T-Z, 1944-1972 (Box 10)
- Pictures Series, 1920-1959
  Contains photographs of staff members from J. Walter Thompson's domestic and international offices, photographs of clients and of some client's display windows, and slides of ads Henderson worked on during his years in the Cincinnati Office.
  - Staff: (Box 11)
    - Antwerp, Belgium, 1949 (Box 11)
    - Chicago, 1934-1949, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Cincinnati, 1927-1935, 5 folders (Box 11)
    - London, 1949-1950, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Mexico, 1949 (Box 11)
    - New York, 1956-1958 (Box 11)
    - San Francisco, 1947 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1959, 9 folders (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough-Ponds:
    - Cincinnati, 1947 (Box 11)
    - London, 1949, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - New York, 1952, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Paris, 1949 (Box 11)
  - General Cigar Co.:
    - New York, 1943-1947, 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Stefenson, Edmund F., 1949 (Box 11)
  - Union Central Life Insurance Co., 1934 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous:
    - London, 1949 (Box 11)
    - Cincinnati, 1933-1934, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Advertisements (slides), 1920- (Box 11)
- Oversize Material
  - Competitive advertisements:
    - Newspaper ads, tear sheets, 1923-1960 (Box 12)
    - Tearsheets, 1923-1960, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Dealer brochures:
    - Crosley Radio Corp., 1929-1930 (Box 12)
    - General Cigar, 1937 (Box 12)
    - Gruen Watch, undated (Box 12)
    - Jergens, 1932-1934 (Box 12)
    - O-ke-doke beermats, 1930s (Box 12)
    - U.S. Playing Card Co., 1937-1943 (Box 12)
  - Pictures:
    - Cartoons, by Howard Henderson, undated, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Drawing of Howard Henderson, 1947 (Box 12)